Mark Zimmerman

Phone: 330-224-8482 <u>markzimmerman1015@gmail.com</u>

SUMMARY:

Newly certified Full-Stack Software Developer seeking employment with an organization that values exceptional work ethic, professionalism, high-character and determination. Beginning a new career in software development after spending 5 years as a professional baseball player with the San Diego Padres, where character traits such as being a strong team player, and leadership on and off the field contributed to a positive culture. Shows strong ability, aptitude and passion for software development. Described by the San Diego Padres management as "a 1%'er and would make an excellent candidate in whatever field of employment he chooses to pursue".

TECHNICAL SKILLS

<u>Programming Languages:</u> JavaScript(ES6), HTML, CSS <u>Libraries & Frameworks:</u> Node.js, React, PostgreSQL, ExpressJS, Bootstrap <u>Tools & Platforms:</u> Git, Github, Netlify, Heroku

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Grace Shopper Project | Ecommerce | https://jerseyzoutlet.onrender.com/

Full-Stack Ecommerce web application selling NFL jerseys.

- Developed front-end components using JavaScript and React.
- Implemented a relational backend with routes, using Express, PostgreSQL, and Node.js.
- Collaborated in a team of 3 full-stack developers during a 3 week sprint using agile workflow.

<u>Tech stack</u>: React, CSS, Axios for front-end API calls; Node, Express, and PostgreSQL for server development; BCrypt for token encryption and sensitive information.

Stranger's Things | React | https://cheery-sopapillas-b87876.netlify.app

A front-end application allowing users to create, edit, and delete posts, as well as message other users.

- Developed React components to create an intuitive user experience.
- Allows users to create, edit, and delete their own posts, as well as send and receive messages from other users.

<u>Tech stack:</u> React, Fetch API

Connect Four | Game | https://charming-scone-2535b3.netlify.app

A two player connect four game, built using DOM manipulation.

- Developed user interface using HTML and CSS.
- Developed game logic using JavaScript.

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Academy Web Development Bootcamp

June 2022 - August 2022

Software Engineering Certificate Full-time, Full Stack JavaScript Web Development Immersive **Baldwin Wallace University**2012-2016

Bachelor of Arts for Pre-Physical Therapy

EXPERIENCE

Package Handler, UPS, Middleburg Heights, OH August 2021 - April 2022 Professional Baseball Player, San Diego Padres, San Diego, California 2016 - 2021

REFERENCES

Available on Request

Mark Zimmerman

Phone: 330-224-8482 <u>markzimmerman1015@gmail.com</u>